Finding Aid for First Congregational Church (Bay City, Mich.) records, 1875-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Congregational Church (Bay City, Mich.) records 1875-1975
First Congregational Church (Bay City, Mich.).
4.5 linear feet and 2 oversize volumes
86754 Ba 2; BA Outsize
Secretary's minutes, board of trustees minutes, church bulletins, newsletters, annual reports and historical booklets.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group is on deposit from the church (donor no. 6006 ) and came to the library in 1978.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Congregational Church of Bay City was established in 1875.
The records include Minutes of Secretary or Clerk of the church, minutes of the Board of Trustees, church bulletins, newsletters, annual reports, financial records, and Sunday School record books.
Subjects:
Bay City (Mich.)--Church history.; Congregational churches--Michigan--Bay City.; First Congregational Church (Bay City, Mich.); Women--Michigan--Bay City.
- Governance records
  - Minutes of Secretary or Clerk of the church, 1875-1919 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Secretary or Clerk of the church, 1920-1938 (Volume 1)
  - Minutes of Clerk of the Church, 1938-1952 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees
    - Minutes, 1892-1913 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1913-1949 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, January 19, 1949-December 17, 1950 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Record of Pew Rent Pledges, 1907-October 19, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's Record, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Church Bulletins, 1914-1975
    - 1914-1961 (Box 2)
      (incomplete)
    - 1962-1975 (Box 3)
  - Church Newsletters, 1951-1975
    - 1951-1961 (Box 3)
      (complete)
    - 1962-1975 (Box 4)
  - Church Annual Reports, 1939-1975 (Box 4)
  - Publications: church history, directories, etc. (Box 4)
  - Membership and financial records (Box 5)
  - Sunday School record books (Box 5)
  - Sunday School record book, 1876-1881 (Volume 2)
Related Material
The researcher should also consult the papers of Ira Butterfield, long-time member of the church, who accumulated related First Congregational Church materials.